- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
- Oh, boy!
A circus.
- 哦，孩子！
马戏团。
Squidward, you didn't tell me
the circus was in town.
章鱼哥，你没告诉我
马戏团在城里。
[gasps]
[喘气]
And it's in your house.
它就在你家里。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
-Oh, good grief.
It's not a circus, you clown.
-噢，真可惜。
这不是马戏团，你这个小丑。
It's an exterminator's
fumigation tent.
这是灭虫者的
熏蒸帐篷。
Somebody's been feeding sea
urchins in this neighborhood,
有人在喂海
这附近的顽童，
and they've infested my house.
他们已经侵扰了我的房子。
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Ooh, what's that up there?
哦，那上面是什么？
- Squidward's circus
is boring,
- 章鱼哥的马戏团
很无聊，
and the cotton candy
is stale.
和棉花糖
已经过时了。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
It's not a circus,
and that's not cotton candy.
这不是马戏团
那不是棉花糖。
D'oh, never mind.
噢，没关系。
- Squidward, are you
going somewhere?
- 章鱼哥，你是吗？
要去某个地方吗？
- I'll be staying at a hotel
for the next few days
- 我会住在酒店
未来几天
for peace and quiet.
为了和平与安静。
-Goodbye!
-Bye!
-再见！
Seasons greetings!
季节的问候！
[festive music]
[节日音乐]
♪ ♪
both: [vocalizing]
两者：[发声]
- [mutters]
- [嘀咕]
- Yes?
- 是的？
- Uh, are you the manager?
- 呃，你是经理吗？
- No, I just play one on TV.
- 不，我只是在电视上播放一首。
I'd like a room.
我想要一间房。
Well, lucky you.
We have one room left,
嗯，你很幸运。
我们还剩一间房
but I just gave it away.
但我刚刚把它放弃了。
- Well, how does
that make me lucky?
- 嗯，怎么样
这让我幸运吗？
- Because I just
gave it to you.
- 因为我只是
把它给了你。
- [mutters]
- [嘀咕]
- Would you like a bell boy?
- 你想要一个行李员吗？
- Why yes, thank you.
- 为什么是的，谢谢。
- Here's your bell, boy.
- 这是你的铃，孩子。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [mutters]
- [嘀咕]
[exhales]
[呼气]
Well, now, this
is very nice indeed.
嗯，现在，这个
确实非常好。
[sighs]
[叹气]
Mm, this is heaven.
嗯，这里就是天堂。
- [laughing excitedly]
- [兴奋地大笑]
- Hello?
- 你好？
Anyone there?
有人在吗？
Hello?
你好？
Hm.
嗯。
[exhales]
[呼气]
- [yelling excitedly]
- [兴奋地大喊]
- Hello?
- 你好？
Did someone just come in?
刚刚有人进来吗？
[both laughing excitedly]
[两人兴奋地大笑]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
- Don't you just love playing
Hotel Slam And Run?
- 你不是只是喜欢玩吗
酒店大满贯和奔跑？
- I enjoy its...
- 我喜欢它...
intellectual challenge.
智力挑战。
[excited gibberish]
[激动的胡言乱语]
- Huh?
- 啊？
All right, I know I heard
something in here.
好吧，我知道我听到了
这里有东西。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Maybe I'm just
not relaxed enough.
也许我只是
不够放松。
[smacks]
[咂嘴]
Hmm.
唔。
- Room service.
- [giggles]
- 客房服务。
- [咯咯笑]
- Yes, hello. Do you have
the blue plate special today?
- 是的，你好。你有吗
今天的蓝盘特别吗？
- Blue plate?
Yes, we have that.
- 蓝盘？
是的，我们有。
Sir, all our plates are blue.
先生，我们所有的盘子都是蓝色的。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- Then I'll have that.
- 那我就来吧。
- Oh, boys.
- 哦，孩子们。
- Yes?
- 是的？
Thanks for filling in
on the phone.
感谢您填写
在电话里。
You may take the order
up to the room now.
您可以接受订单
现在到房间了。
Here's your reward.
这是你的奖励。
[both barking]
[两人都吠叫]
[knocking]
[敲门声]
- Room service.
- 客房服务。
- Come in.
- 进来。
[both shouting excitedly]
[两人兴奋地大喊]
- Squidward?
- 章鱼哥？
What a happy surprise.
多么令人高兴的惊喜啊。
- SpongeBob, aren't you
going to introduce me?
- 海绵宝宝，不是吗
要介绍我吗？
- Oh, it's Squidward, Patrick,
- 哦，这是章鱼哥，帕特里克，
our next-door neighbor
and best friend.
我们的隔壁邻居
和最好的朋友。
- Well, if you says so.
- 好吧，如果你这么说的话。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
Get off me!
放开我！
What are you doing
in this hotel?
你在做什么
在这家酒店？
- This hotel is hosting
- 这家酒店正在接待
the annual
Jelly Fishing Convention.
年度
果冻捕捞大会。
Jelly Fishing Convention?
果冻捕捞大会？
- Yes.
- 是的。
And my room is over there.
我的房间就在那里。
- And that's my room in there.
- 那是我的房间。
both: Squidward's
in the middle!
两者：章鱼哥的
在中间！
Squidward's in the middle!
章鱼哥在中间！
- Conga line!
- 康加线！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
both: ♪ Squidward's
in the middle ♪
两者：♪ 章鱼哥的
在中间♪
♪ Squidward's in the middle ♪
♪ 章鱼哥在中间 ♪
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[exhales]
[呼气]
all: ♪ Squidward's
in the middle ♪
全部：♪ 章鱼哥的
在中间♪
♪ Squidward's in the middle ♪
♪ 章鱼哥在中间 ♪
- You stay away from me.
- 你离我远点。
I don't want to see
either of you
我不想看到
你们中的任何一个
in any part of this hotel.
在这家酒店的任何地方。
[groans]
[呻吟]
I used to love the conga.
我以前很喜欢康加舞。
Ahh, the hotel spa.
啊，酒店的水疗中心。
Mm, this massage feels great.
嗯，这个按摩感觉棒极了。
You have magic fingers.
你有神奇的手指。
[exhales]
[呼气]
both: Squidward!
两人：章鱼哥！
Magic fingers!
神奇的手指！
- No!
- 不！
Stay away from me!
离我远点！
- Huh.
- 嗯。
Oh, we really do
have magic fingers.
哦，我们真的这么做
有魔法手指。
- Oh, yes, I've still got
a dancer's body.
- 哦，是的，我还有
舞者的身体。
One.
一。
Two.
二。
One.
一。
Two.
二。
Huh?
啊？
both: Squidward!
两人：章鱼哥！
- Stay away from me.
- 离我远点。
- Heave!
- Ho!
- 举起！
- 嗬！
- Heave!
- 举起！
- No SpongeBob.
- 没有海绵宝宝。
No Patrick.
没有帕特里克。
[exhales]
[呼气]
Ah, peace and quiet.
啊，和平与安静。
[panicked shouts]
[惊慌的喊叫]
both: Squidward!
两人：章鱼哥！
- Leave me alone!
- 请别打扰我！
- Heave!
- Ho!
- 举起！
- 嗬！
[gargling]
[漱口]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Finally.
最后。
[groans]
[呻吟]
[creepy musical flourish]
[令人毛骨悚然的音乐盛宴]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Hm.
嗯。
That's better.
这样更好。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Stay away from me.
离我远点。
I'm warning you.
我警告你。
I want to be alone.
我想单独待一会儿。
[shudders]
[颤抖]
- Oh, well, if you
want to be alone,
- 哦，好吧，如果你
想要一个人呆着，
don't go into the room
behind you.
不要进入房间
在你身后。
Wait, are you two
in there already?
等等，你们两个吗
已经在那里了？
- No, silly.
- 不，傻瓜。
That's where the jelly fishing
convention is.
这就是钓果冻的地方
康福特群岛
- Welcome, Jelly Fisher.
- 欢迎，果冻费舍尔。
You must be a newbie.
你一定是个新手。
- Huh?
- 啊？
[stammering]
[结巴]
- Jelly Fishing!
Whoo-hoo!
- 果冻钓鱼！
呼呼！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Welcome, newbie!
- 欢迎，新手！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Jelly hug.
- 果冻拥抱。
- [yells]
- [大喊]
Hm?
嗯？
Nooooooooooo!
不呜呜！
All: Jelly Fishing.
Jelly Fishing.
全部：果冻钓鱼。
果冻钓鱼。
Jelly Fishing.
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
both: Hi, Squidward.
两人：嗨，章鱼哥。
- Squidward,
everyone loves you.
- 章鱼哥，
每个人都爱你。
Are you having the funnest
fun fun fun time ever?
你有最好玩的吗
有趣有趣的有趣时光吗？
- I am not fun.
- 我不好玩。
Everybody loves me so much,
they won't let me leave.
大家都很爱我，
他们不会让我离开。
- Hey, Squidward,
we love you, man.
- 嘿，章鱼哥，
我们爱你，伙计。
- You belong with us now.
- 你现在属于我们了。
- Say, if I put
that dumb thing on,
- 说，如果我把
那个愚蠢的东西，
I can sneak out of here without
anybody knowing it's me.
我可以偷偷溜出这里，无需
任何人都知道是我。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[chuckles]
Goodbye, jelly-smellies.
[笑声]
再见，果冻味。
I'm outta here, and back
to peace and quiet in my room.
我离开这里又回来了
我的房间里安静祥和。
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- All right, Jelly Fishers,
- 好吧，果冻渔民，
it's the moment
you've all been waiting for.
就是现在
你们都一直在等待。
- [cheering]
- [欢呼]
- Let the annual
- 让每年
Jellyfish Mascot Hunt begin!
水母吉祥物狩猎开始！
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Jellyfish Mascot Hunt?
- 水母吉祥物狩猎？
[hollering]
[喊叫]
[yells]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[hollering]
[喊叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Huh?
What's this?
- 啊？
这是什么？
Zapper?
扎珀？
[beep]
[嘟]
- Whoop whoop whoop!
- 呼呼呼呼！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Zap me.
- 攻击我。
[yells]
[喊叫]
- [laughs]
Zapper.
- [笑]
扎珀。
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[zaps]
[电击]
both: Zap me!
两人：打我！
[zaps]
[电击]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
both: Oh, boy!
两人：噢，孩子！
[zaps]
[电击]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Yes--
- 是的 -
[zaps]
[电击]
- Hello, Pest Control?
- 你好，害虫防治？
I'm calling
from the Hotel Halibut.
我正在打电话
We've got a horrible
infestation
我们有一个可怕的
侵扰
of jelly fish...
海蜇的...
fanatics.
狂热分子。
- More zaps.
- Zap me.
- 更多的攻击。
- 攻击我。
Send exterminators now!
立即派出灭虫人员！
[sirens]
[警报声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- I sure hope Squidward
got out okay.
- 我当然希望章鱼哥
出来了还好。
- Squidward?
- 章鱼哥？
You must introduce me
some day.
你一定要介绍我
有一天。
- Hm?
- 嗯？
- ♪ I've got peace and quiet ♪
- ♪ 我很平静 ♪
♪ I've got peace and quiet
Whoo ♪
♪ 我有平静与安宁
呼♪
♪ I've got peace and quiet ♪
♪ 我有平静和安宁 ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]